

# Johnson Onaji L Product Designer

In my 5+ years in product design, I have focused on crafting user experiences and design systems for software, web and mobile products. I'm passionate about applying consumer psychology for an interaction science-backed user centered design



WORK EXPERIENCE

**Product Designer** 

Nigeria Medical Asso. (NMA)

Bank- X Core Banking App

ik- A core barrking App

Apr-May, 2024

Contract

Full time

Full time

**OTECH Microfinance Bank** 

Jan-March, 2024

#### **Faculty Lecturer**

APTECH Computer Education Calabar - NYSC

August, 2023 - July 2024

June-July, 2024

#### Product Designer

Kimpact Development Initiative (9ja Talks mobile app)

Nov, 2022 - July 2023

- Analyzed and interpreted User research data
- Converting User research analytics into data-informed problem solving.
- Understanding and Analysing Product brief to infer design ideas.
- Creating Sketch, Low, and High fidelity wireframes for the mobile app.
- Creating and Implementing Interactions and Animations across Wireframes.
- Working directly with my product manager and giving useful feedback & suggestions upon demand.

### Interaction Designer

Full time

KDI 2023 Nigeria Elections Data Room (Kimpact Magic Screen)

Feb 2023 - March 2023

- Analyzed and interpreted real time Election data
- Converting raw data into concise, understandable form
- Creating visualisations for the data generated
- Created interactions for the visualised data using figma

## Product Designer

Remote

Technolix Nigeria Ltd (Suretrip mobile app)

February 2022 – May 2022

- Leading and overseeing the user experience of the start up product from conception to launch in partnership with web designers, engineers, UX researchers and content strategists.
- Strategizing with the Product design team on best possible UI/UX strategies to meet market demand.
- Understanding and Analysing Product brief to infer design ideas for the startup. Working directly with the Managing Director and giving useful feedback & suggestions upon demand.



EDUCATION

Benue State University, Makurdi

Grade: First Class 2016 - 2021

Carried out a project research to Improve Search Engine Result Pages Through Abstract Extension by Summarization using the python NLP models.





Language

English

Relational skills

Communication skills

Team player

Result driven

Leadership skill

Empathy

Technical skills

UI/UX Design

Frontend Web Development

Brand Identity Design

Document Design

Video Editing

Data Visualisation & Analysis

Basic Python Programming

#### Tools

Figma, Protopie, Mirror

HTML, CSS, Javascript

Adobe Illustrator

Adobe Indesign

Adobe Premier e Pro

Microsoft Power Bi

Python Jupyter IDE



Foundations of User Experience Design - Alison, 2023

User Interface Design with Figma - Alison, 2023

Diploma in Computer Interaction -Emmies Advanced Institute of Technology, 2014